<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<guide self="appendices/contributing/">
<chapter>
<title>为本文档贡献自己的力量</title>

<body>
<p>非常欢迎为本文档添砖加瓦，哪怕是印刷错误或一段新的内容，您都可以通过登录Bugzilla<uri link="https://bugs.gentoo.org">bugs.gentoo.org</uri>来提交。</p>

<p>编辑有权按照他们的想法来修改意见书。除了显而易见的请求、轻微的错字更正及格式修复不会讨论外，其他任何重大的变化都首先要讨论，然后才能提交。</p>

<p>本文档的授权协议是<uri link="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</uri>。如果这是问题，请不要提交任何东西。</p>

<p>本文档是使用 DevBook XML 生成系统产生的。您可以从Subversion下载系统以及相关的XML文件的快照。您还可以在URL中使用<c>index.html</c>替换成<c>text.xml</c>来查看任何网页的 XML。如果你只愿意使用纯文本，那也没关系了<d/>格式可以由我们的其他人来简单处理。</p>

<subsection>
  <title>在哪里可以找到源代码</title>
  <body>

<p>当前源码放在<uri link="https://gitweb.gentoo.org/proj/devmanual.git">git.gentoo.org</uri>。对于Gentoo开发者访问<c>git+ssh://git@git.gentoo.org/proj/devmanual.git</c>。非开发者通过输入<c>git clone git://anongit.gentoo.org/proj/devmanual.git</c>来复制仓库。对于更喜欢使用pull requests来提交补丁的人来说也可以使用放在<uri link="https://github.com/gentoo/devmanual.gentoo.org">GitHub</uri>上的源码。</p>

<p>若要生成 devmanual，只需在仓库的顶层目录中运行<c>make</c>。你需要安装用于转换XML成HTML的<c>xsltproc</c>(来自<c>dev-libs/libxslt</c>)和用于把整个文档中使用的SVG图表转换成PNG的<c>convert</c>(来自<c>media-gfx/imagemagick</c>)。</p>
  </body>
</subsection>

</body>

<section>
<title>DevBook XML 的快速入门</title>
<body>

<p>
DevBook XML is heavily based on <uri link="https://www.gentoo.org/doc/en/xml-guide.xml">GuideXML</uri> and many tags are similar, if not the same. The main differences
occur in layout which are designed to make a large-scale publication easier
to produce and manage using a hierarchical tree system. Before starting off you
really should first examine the GuideXML guide in a reasonable amount of depth.
</p>

<subsection>
<title>Differences from GuideXML</title>
<body>

<dl>
  <dt>
    Indentation
  </dt>
  <dd>
    <p>
      Indent when needed <d/> you should not indent any section flow elements such as
      <c>&lt;subsection&gt;</c> but do indent tables, lists and definition lists.
      Do <e>not</e> indent text in ordinary paragraph blocks.
    </p>
  </dd>
  <dt>
    Code Samples
  </dt>
  <dd>
    <p>
      You can use the normal GuideXML tag <c>&lt;pre&gt;</c> when you need no syntax
      highlighting. When you need syntax highlighting use the <c>&lt;codesample&gt;</c>
      tag along with a <c>lang</c> attribute <d/> usually you want this to be set to
      <c>ebuild</c> to syntax highlight ebuild code snippets.
    </p>
  </dd>
  <dt>
    Hierarchy
  </dt>
  <dd>
    <p>
      The whole document is organized as a tree. Each directory can contain one
      document. Each document can inherit multiple sub-documents using the
      <c>&lt;include&gt;</c> flag. You <b>must</b> ensure that the <c>self</c> tag
      in each document correctly points to the relative path of the document from
      the root node so that the tree-walking algorithms work correctly.
    </p>
  </dd>
</dl>

</body>
</subsection>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Style Guidelines</title>
<body>

<ul>
  <li>
  This document is in British English. Submissions in other kinds of English are
  welcome, but they may have their spelling corrected.
  </li>
  <li>
  Third person form should be used rather than first.
  </li>
  <li>
  This is not a formal document. The writing style is intended to be
  professional but readable.
  </li>
  <li>
  When using in-sentence hyphens as punctuation <d/> like this <d/> use a space,
  followed by the <c>&lt;d/&gt;</c> tag. The build system will automatically turn
  this into a proper Unicode long dash.
  </li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>

</guide>
